<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming tools in data science on Programming tools for data science</title>
    <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming tools in data science on Programming tools for data science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ptds.samorso.ch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>R/RStudio installation and setup</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/r_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 13:10:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/r_install/</guid>
      <description>1. Installing R and RStudio 1.1 Installing R We start with installing the latest version of R (4.0.2 as of August 14, 2020). R itself is similar to an engine and chassis of a car, that is a bare minimum so that you can start driving. You need to follow steps below:
 Visit https://cran.r-project.org and click on &amp;ldquo;Download R for &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, where &amp;hellip; coresponds to your operating system. Depending on the operating system:  For Mac: download &amp;ldquo;R-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Coding Style Guide</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:18:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/style/</guid>
      <description>Good coding style is like using correct punctuation. You can manage without it, but it sure makes things easier to read. Hadley Wickham  Introduction A language is a tool that allows human beings to interact and communicate with each other. The clearer we express ourselves, the better an idea is transferred from our mind to the other. The same applies to programming languages: concise, clear and consistent codes are easier to read and/or edit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General information</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/general/</guid>
      <description>Location and Time  Location: Anthropole/3174 Time: 8:30 - 12 (see the lectures schedule for more details)  Course Websites  Course website: https://ptds.samorso.ch/ Online textbook: http://r.smac-group.com/ Discussion Forum: on slack  Course Staff Instructor  Name: Samuel Orso Email: Samuel.Orso@unil.ch Office: Anthropole/3090.1 Office Hours: Appointment may be made upon request. find me on GitHub  Teaching Assistant  Name: Aleksandr Shemendyuk Email: aleksandr.shemendyuk@unil.ch Office: Extranef/107 Office Hours: Appointment may be made upon request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Each homework is graded and should be finished in due time; a penalty is applied for late submission (see the syllabus).
gantt dateFormat YYYY-MM-DD title Schedule for the homeworks section Homeworks homework 0 :active, des1, 2021-09-27, 1d homework 1 :active, des2, 2021-10-04, 2021-10-10 homework 2 :active, des3, 2021-10-11, 2021-10-24 project proposal:crit, active, des4, 2021-11-01, 6d homework 3 :active, des5, 2021-10-25, 2021-11-14 homework 4 :active, des6, 2021-11-15, 2021-11-28 section Deadlines homework 1 :crit, 2021-10-10, 1d homework 2 :crit, 2021-10-24, 1d project proposal:crit, 2021-11-07, 1d homework 3 :crit, 2021-11-14, 1d homework 4 :crit, 2021-11-28, 1d  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-oriented workflow</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:19:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/workflow/</guid>
      <description>It’s like agreeing that we will all drive on the left or the right. A hallmark of civilization is following conventions that constrain your behavior a little, in the name of public safety. Jenny Bryan  Introduction In this tutorial we will learn key aspects of making a good research project:
 reproducible portable self-contained  In data science context, reproducibility means that the whole analysis can be recreated (or repeated) from the fresh start and raw data and get exactly the same results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #0</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 16:40:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw0/</guid>
      <description>Homework generously provided by the Data Science in Business Analytics class.
This homework is optional and is not graded.
 In this optional tutorial you will get an overview of the basic programming concepts in R and main data types. Just enough to get you up and running essential R code. However, for true &amp;ldquo;beginners&amp;rdquo;, we highly recommend going through Advanced R - Chapter &amp;lsquo;Foundations&amp;rsquo; from which the content of this assignment is mainly (mostly) inspired by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course description</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/coursedescr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/coursedescr/</guid>
      <description>This class is intended to introduce to the students a wide range of programming tools using the R language. Tentative list of topics that will be discussed in this class are listed below:
 Reproducible research: knitr and rmarkdown Version control: GitHub Introduction to programming: Data structures, logical operators, control structures and functions Visualizations: Exploratory data analysis with Base R and ggplot2 R packages: Construction of R-packages using devtools, roxygen2 and pkgdown Communication: webiste creation via blogdown, Web application via shiny Web scraping: Automatic extraction of data from websites using SelectorGadget, rvest and quantmod, regular expression High performance computing: R and C++ integration via Rcpp, parallel computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/project/output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/project/output/</guid>
      <description>Presentations of the projects are held the 2021-12-20. You have 15 minutes of presentation + 5 minutes of questions per group. Each member should present a piece of the presentation.
 The output of your project must be:
 An awesome project! A super R-package that can be directly installed from your GitHub repository. More specifically you should make sure:   you have a DESCRIPTION file with all necessary information including, but not limited to, Package title, general description, dependencies, license, and imports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary material</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/lectures/additional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/lectures/additional/</guid>
      <description>Try the RMarkdown Shiny app</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 16:46:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/grading/</guid>
      <description>There are 60 points in total for this class. The final grades are given as follows:
   Grade Points     6.0 57-60   5.5 52-56   5.0 47-51   4.5 42-46   4.0 37-41   3.5 32-36   3.0 27-31   2.5 22-26   2.0 17-21   1.5 12-16   1.0 0-11    Learning outcomes will be assessed based on the performances within each of the following categories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #1</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw1/</guid>
      <description>Deadline: 2021-10-10 11:59pm
To submit your work, simply push it to the dedicated repository created for your group.
We will grade only the latest files prior to the deadline. Any ulterior modifications are pointless.
 The objectives of this homework assignment are the followings:
 Build your own RMarkdown document. Master different aspects of RMarkdown syntax. Become familiar with GitHub as a collaborative tool.  This homework must be accomplished using GitHub and respect the following requirements:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/project/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/project/proposal/</guid>
      <description>Project proposal submission deadline is 2021-11-07 11:59pm.
 The group project is a major goal of this class (50% of the final grade). In order to make sure that your project is on the right track, you must submit a project proposal for reviewing.
The project proposal is a RMarkdown document (3 pages max) submitted on dedicated GitHub repository and must comprise the following sections:
 Goals and impacts: describe briefly the rationale of your project, you overall objectives and potential impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #1 solutions</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw1-sol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw1-sol/</guid>
      <description>The objectives of this homework assignment are the followings:
 Build your own RMarkdown document. Master different aspects of RMarkdown syntax. Become familiar with GitHub as a collaborative tool.  Note the following requirements:
 All members of the group must commit at least once. All commit messages must be reasonably clear and meaningful. Your GitHub repository must include at least one issue containing some form of TO DO list.  In your repository, create a RMarkdown file called hw1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic regression</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/logistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/tutorials/logistic/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this tutorial is to show how to write your own program for estimating a logistic regression. Note that the goal is purely educational since the logistic regression has already solid implementations in R.
Introduction Logistic regression is one of most famous tool to model binary data. It is often introduced in under-graduate class of statistics and machine learning.
For illustration, we fit a logistic regression on the titanic dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:46:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/communication/</guid>
      <description>Slack We will be using Slack for class-related discussion and questions, to help you benefit from each other’s questions and the collective knowledge of your classmates and instructors. Questions can be posted to the entire class (for content-related questions). I encourage you to ask questions if you are struggling to understand a concept, and to answer your classmates’ questions when you can.
Email Most matters, public or private, should be addresssed through Slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #2</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw2/</guid>
      <description>Deadline: 2021-10-24 11:59pm
To submit your work, simply push it to the dedicated repository created for your group.
We will grade only the latest files prior to the deadline. Any ulterior modifications are pointless.
 The objectives of this homework assignment are the followings:
 Learn how program effectively using if/else and iterations statements; Become familiar with using data frame objects and mapping packages; Constructing a portfolio; Become familiar with GitHub and use it as a collaborative tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #3</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 16:40:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/homeworks/hw3/</guid>
      <description>Deadline: 2021-11-14 11:59pm To submit your work, simply push it to the dedicated repository created for your group.
We will grade only the latest files prior to the deadline. Any ulterior modifications are pointless.
 The objectives of this homework assignment are the followings:
 Become competent at programming effectively using if/else and iterations statements; Learn how to program effectively using functions and think like a programmer; Improve your collaborative skills via GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/material/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 19:08:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/material/</guid>
      <description>Laptops Bring a laptop to the class every week if you have one. We encourage students to work collaboratively, so we would like to have at least one laptop for every 2 or 3 students. Since the homeworks and the project are the work of a team, we encourage you to team-up with students that possess a laptop. In the case you plan to buy a laptop, remember that the students from Swiss Universities have preferential prices via the Neptun Projekt or the EPFL&amp;rsquo;s Poseidon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convinced?</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/final/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 13:39:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/syllabus/final/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composition</title>
      <link>https://ptds.samorso.ch/group/groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptds.samorso.ch/group/groups/</guid>
      <description>Here is the group composition :
Group 1  Aëllya Monney Rémy Tombola Laurène Hsieh Visesa Jain Corinne Schönholzer  Group 2  Matteo Gross Alessia Di Pietro Martina Celic Ana Gabriela Garcia Laura Lo Priore  Group 3  Ismail Sarah Abdulghafor Nada Lugon Waren Beijer Enzo Labinot Ismaili  Group 4  Daniel Szenes Ozgur Aydemir Francesco Darino Sophie La Gennusa Louis del Perugia  Group 5  Marie Bellier Rodrigues Telo Ramos Vania Renger Xavier Finini Massimo Likoska Meri  Group 6  Colin Steffe Daniel Welz Guillaume Bilocq Jasmine Mawjee Virany Kho  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
